# Michael Jerred

mjerred.com mjerred.work@gmail.com github.com/MikeJerred stackoverflow.com/u/4854046

## Profile

I am a contract web developer with 16 years of development experience, 7 of which have been working professionally on a variety of web applications. I first started coding when I was a kid and it has been a lifelong passion, as a result I am able to pickup new languages and technologies with ease.

## Expertise

- Angular 1 to 7 (continuously since 2015)
- Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, jQuery
- ∨ C#, LINQ, Node.js, Express
- SQL, Entity Framework, MongoDB, Neo4j, Apache Solr, ElasticSearch
- N-Tier, Event Sourcing, DDD, CQRS
- Windows, Linux

## Achievements

- Led the development and designed the architecture of the front-end for a new greenfield project (called Merlin) using Angular 7.
- Led the development and designed the architecture for a greenfield project (called The Lawyer Market Intelligence). By introducing AngularJS to the company and structuring work so that it could be done in parallel more effectively, there were significant gains in productivity and these methodologies saw continued use in future projects.
- > Built a data migration tool to move a large data set from an existing SQL database into a new project using event sourcing and CQRS. I built the tool using Rx to do work asynchronously, so that it ran fast enough to complete within the target window.
- Built an open-source npm package to provide strongly typed reactive forms for Angular.

# Commercial Projects

Merlin November 2018 - Current

Deloitte & AstraZeneca

I am the principal front-end developer and architect on a new tool which calculates the costs of clinical trials. I am responsible for structuring the front-end code (Angular, Typescript), giving direction to and mentoring other developers, and writing code. More recently I also been working with the back-end (Java, MongoDB) as the project required more resources in that area.

## **XpKit Analytics Library**

May 2018

**Imagination** 

I built a library to replicate the functionality of the segment io analytics library, but with some adjustments. I built it as an npm package using Typescript, complete with Jasmine unit tests and generated documentation.

#### Wan Li Portfolio Site

December 2017

Wan Li

I built a UX designer's portfolio site using Angular with some interesting animations.

### **Dragon CMS Project**

January 2017 – July 2017

Centaur Media

I worked on building a large new project built using Domain Driven Design, event sourcing and CQRS. Event messages were sent from the browser to the server via WebSockets, so that multiple users on the site would be able to see each others changes in real time. The front-end was built using Angular 4, and the back-end using C# Web API and SQL Server. My specific role was to build parts of the front and back-end, advise on architectural decisions, and create a tool to perform data migration.

LMI Reskin November 2016

Centaur Media

I did front-end coding on this cosmetic redesign of an existing site.

## The Lawyer Market Intelligence

October 2015

Centaur Media

I was the lead developer on this brand new site, which including building a custom CMS. I designed the architecture for the front-end with a combination of AngularJs, LESS and Typescript; and built a skeleton back-end to interface with the database. After this initial phase the other developers joined in and we each worked on separate modules. Using this approach we were able to develop with a high degree of parallelization, and finished the project ahead of schedule.

# Open Source Projects

### ngx-strong-forms

March 2019

I built an npm package to provides strongly-typed reactive forms for Angular.

## **GWToolboxpp**

July 2016 - April 2018

I contributed to a video game modification project using C++ and x86 assembly.

# **Employment History**

### Linnet Digital

November 2016 - Current

This is my limited company through which I do contract work.

### Centaur Media

August 2014 - Feburary 2016

My role at Centaur was to write code for various ASP.NET projects, fixing bugs and developing new features on existing sites; as well as creating brand new sites, as part of a team of 6-7 developers. The sites were built using C# for the back-end, with SQL Server for the database and Apache Solr for creating indices. A combination of AngularJs, Bootstrap, Typescript, LESS, jQuery and Knockout were used for the front-end. Mercurial was used for version management.

One of my main achievements was to introduce the AngularJs framework to the team, and use this to create the front-end architecture for two major new projects. These were a great success and the company is now using Angular as a standard for future projects.

#### **Acturis**

August 2012 - June 2014

I worked as a junior developer using C#, Moq, SQL, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

## Qualifications

### 2008 - 2012 MSci. Mathematics and Physics

University of Bristol

#### 2008 **UK Physics Olympiad**

Gold medal & one of 15 chosen to attend the International Olympiad preparation camp

University of Oxford

### 2006 - 2008 5x A2 Level, Physics Advanced Extension Award

Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Further Maths, Further Maths Additional The Manchester Grammar School